Liam Armstrong

Toronto, ON · liam@liam-armstrong.com

github.com/liam-armstrong · linkedin.com/in/liam-armstrong · liam-armstrong.com

Profile

Computer science and commerce student with years of experience building solutions to unique problems using technology. Effective communicator who possesses a strong aptitude for problem solving and uses a commitment to high quality in order to tackle tough and exciting challenges.

Skills

Languages: Java, Python, C++, JavaScript (ES6), HTML, CSS
Frameworks and Libraries: Django, React, Redux, AngularJS, Bootstrap, JQuery
Technologies and Tools: Docker, Git, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Unix Systems

Education

Work Experience

University of British Columbia

Vancouver. BC

B.A. Interdisciplinary Studies, Computer Science and Commerce

Sept 2017 - 2021 2018 - 2019

Deans List Scholar

University of Toronto - Centre for Advanced Coating Technologies

Toronto, ON

A materials science and mechanical engineering lab that conducts research in the areas of thermal spray coatings and plasma processing.

Technical and Administration Support

June 2019 - Aug 2019

- Assisted Dr. Thomas Coyle with lab management and IT problem solving
- Built an automated citation system using XML and JavaScript in order to save 4 hours per grant application and university activity report

Kids Help Phone Toronto, ON

A Canadian and world leader known for its expertise and continuous innovation as Canada's only 24/7 mental health counselling and information service for young people.

Fundraising Intern

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Worked to further Kids Help Phone's corporate relationships by facilitating communication, building reports and organizing fundraising events, raising \$300,000+ at the Golf Classic presented by Nestle
- Created a Python web scraping script to find and process event and sponsorship prospects, generating over 500 productive leads

Project Management Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Assisted Special Projects team to organize the Child Helpline International Consultation, a biennial, 1000 attendee, international conference
- Streamlined our invoicing process for conference attendees by creating Excel tools to generate and send documents, saving over 100 hours of manual work and ensuring consistently flawless documents

Intrst Financial Toronto, ON

Intrst was a leading financial product discovery platform targeted at Generation Z. Using product comparisons and articles, Intrst helped teens understand their finances.

Co-Founder and Chief Technology Officer

Oct 2016 - Jul 2017

- Designed, built and deployed the company's web site and application as primary developer, gathering 10,000 page views in one week
- Used Agile methodologies to track team of four direct reports responsible for on-going product optimization, maintenance and expansion
- Generated specifications and chose technologies for initial site and all feature expansions based on feedback from stakeholders

Extra-Curricular Activities

nwHacks Vancouver, BC

nwHacks is western Canada's biggest hackathon, where 700 attendees organize into teams and collaborate on technology projects for 24h and compete for prizes.

Hackathon Logistics Coordinator

Sept 2017 - May 2019

- Presented and prepared nwHacks 2019 opening ceremonies to 700 attendees, setting an inclusive tone that lead to a record setting 133 project submissions
- Curated workshop on basic software engineering techniques and tools, allowing 100 first time event attendees to submit projects

Projects

Two Eyes Out

2eo.liam-armstrong.com

Aug 2018 - Present

Django REST API, React and Redux

If a class is full at UBC, students cannot register until a seat opens in their desired section. This app watches course listings and alerts the user once a seat is available.

- · Self designed, implemented and deployed full stack system
- Django backend uses PostgreSQL and Redis to manages users, scrapes course listings and sends notification emails
- · React and Redux front end allows users to manage their listings
- · Full stack app is containerized with Docker and hosted on an AWS EC2 Instance

210 Calendar

github.com/liam-armstrong/cpsc-210-calendar Sept 2018 - Dec 2018

Java, FXML

A desktop calendar application with task scheduling and aggregation

- Object hierarchy designed in accordance with OOP principals
- · Utilizes software architecture design patterns for robust and readable functionality
- Connects to open source location database to automatically set time zone
- · Received perfect project grade in UBC CPSC 210 every week throughout entire term